# JEFFREY MOORE

User Experience Designer

Phone: 267-239-3267

Email: jeffreym@knightmoore.com

**URL**: <u>www.knightmoore.com</u>

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

User Experience Designer with 8+ years of experience in multiple professional environments. Currently I research, design, and implement the visual system and overall user experience for my companies' internal digital assets; synchronizing brand layout and tone while maintaining detailed style guides. I am leading several visual experience design initiatives to increase the effectiveness of the company's internal digital strategy, to implement enhanced email delivery protocols, and to create a new dashboard style company intranet.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Digital Experience Designer**

AmeriHealth Caritas February 2014 - Present

- Designing wireframes, user flows, style tiles, component libraries and high-fidelity mock-ups for web based, apps, widgets, and websites to ensure and document a consistent information architecture using rapid prototyping technologies such as Photoshop, Illustrator, and Axure Pro.
- Architecting accessible, 508 compliant visual designs and user interfaces using HTML, CSS and JavaScript in a .NET based development environment in conjunction with Digital Developers and Content Producers, using Dreamweaver and CrownPeak
- Leading user experience initiatives, by employing UI and UX best practices and web accessibility standards, crafting research documents designed to be the source of truth for current and future UX projects and championing Agile methodologies and Scrum processes and a self-managed team dynamic.
- Leveraging qualitative and quantitative data from analytics, user feedback and focus groups to craft a thoughtful and high quality, design for our company intranet.
- Establishing workflows, style guides, and design standards documentation for web sites, email blasts and digital signage that enhanced the effectiveness of client presentations, reinforced internal brand campaigns, and increased product value for clients.

## **Freelance Digital Artist**

KnightMoore Digital March 2012 - Present

- Crafting responsive websites and user experiences with WordPress and non-CMS, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript in Adobe
  Dreamweaver.
- Guiding clients through the full design life cycle, providing user research, wireframes, mock-ups and final designs while educating clients on the importance of a brand centered web presence and effective client focused design.
- Applying storytelling fundamentals and story driven design concepts to create a variety of branding and marketing assets such as custom graphics, character designs, logo designs, illustrations, DVD covers and book covers using Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Specializing in working with small business owners and creative professionals crafting unique brands and client focused web experiences.

#### Web and Graphic Designer

Magnetron Valve Corporation March 2011 – May 2013

- Developing a full stack web solution and co-branding campaign that combined their two existing websites into one site using HTML, CSS, SQL and JavaScript.
- Creating responsive landing pages, Ui components, and print components for mixed media marketing campaigns that
  increased customer feedback and provided critical data to improve product designs and customer targeting ultimately
  increasing client feedback and repeat sales.
- Crafting HTML emails for newsletter campaigns designed to increase customer engagement.

• Designing a variety of web and print collateral using Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign.

#### Jr. Programmer

American Law Institute
November 2010 – November 2011

- Working with Senior Programmers developing server-side applications and static webpages for corporate website and instructional microsites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Cold Fusion.
- Collaborating with graphic designers to develop elegant front-end user interfaces.
- Providing top notch customer service to lawyers and clients for virtual training and webinars.

#### **Graphic Design Intern**

Aurora Imaging Company June 2010 – September 2010

- Working with Lead Graphic Designer on a variety of client projects building web page mock ups, training manuals, video graphics and web assets using Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign.
- Establishing brand elements and standards focusing on visual design, typography, color, layout, and tone in order to provide maximum value for clients.

### **Logistics and Readiness Petty Officer**

United States Navy Reserves December 2003 – March 2006

- Performing a variety of design, logistics, and administrative tasks in support of sea-based operations both domestic and abroad
- Crafting organizational systems and spreadsheets using Microsoft Excel to increase the efficiency of logistics reporting methods.
- Establishing expert verbal and written communication skills by preparing daily and monthly reports in Microsoft Word that were delivered to high ranking officers for evaluating supply and troop movements in theater.

## Information Systems Supervisor, Electronic Keying Materials Clerk (EKMS)

**United States Navy** 

September 1999 - September 2003

- Leveraging modern information systems technologies in support of fleet operations abroad.
- Attaining the rank of E-5 and maintained Top Secret security clearance.
- Completing numerous qualifications including the Enlisted Surface Warfare (ESWS) qualification.
- Training on the use and maintenance of microcomputer systems and radio frequency antenna.
- Supervising lower ranked sailors in technical and maintenance projects to maintain ship readiness standards.

### **EDUCATION**

## Art Institute of Philadelphia

BS Web, Design and Interactive Media Graduated Sept 2010

#### **US Navy, Navy College**

Military Information Systems Technology 1999 – 2003

#### **New Jersey City University**

Digital Illustration, Sophomore 1997 – 1999

### LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

# **Accessibility for Web Design**

Lynda.com

# **User Experience Design Certification**

Lynda.com

## **SKILLS**

Code: HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS 3, LESS, JavaScript,

**Software**: Photoshop, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, InDesign, Adobe Creative Suite, Axure Pro, Gravit Designer, InVision, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Project, RMG Design Studio,

**CMS**: Word Press, CrownPeak, TeamSite, Workfront, SharePoint, CVENT